We must first understand the Android system source code directly structure to lay the foundation for
it must be learning.
So let's get started.
Wow.
Wow, wow, wow.
If you haven't downloaded the AOSP source code yet, you can you see us dot Android dot com to read
through the source code and follow along with this tutorial.
What if you want to download the RSP source code?
Please follow the instructions from AOSP download tutorials.
So the basic idea of this session is to give you a very high level overview of RSP folders.
So we'll will go through each folders one by one, and I will try to explain what each folders are meant
for.
So the first folder we have got is a team which stands for Android one time.
So this folder contains the modules related to Android runtime operating environment.
All the air related modules can be found here, including DEX compilers, JVM, Dalvik Meal, etc. How
open the MSP project in ingilizce.
So here you can find all the folders coming under the Areas Bee Project.
So the first one is our team, which stands for Android runtime.
So as we discussed, it contains all the dependent modules required for the Android runtime to function.
So here we can find the Dalvik medium and open duty game.
And similarly, there are a lot of other dependent modules which are necessary for Android runtime to
function.
So next is Bionic.
Bionic is Android Custom See Library, Mat Library and a dynamic link so you can find bionic here and
inside that.
You can find all the library and support of the modules for C and C++.
If you open the read me, you can read more information about different folders within bionics.
So, for example, this folder contains all the modules for the Mac library, and similarly, Lipsy
Lipsy contains all the C related modules, and the dynamic linker interface is available in Lib Bill
and the Lib Standard C++ is available in this particular folder.
The dynamic linker and the uni text can be found here.
The benchmarks can be found under this path.
Next, we have bootable.
The bootable folder consists of the boot related code, so it contains the bootloader OTA, over-the-air
update and some modules for the recovery mechanism.
So in in the we have the bootable folder here which we could find the bootloader and the recovery for
it.
Up next, we have the Build folder the Build a folder consists of to make files for the build system
so you can find the EMV setup up passage while here and some common shell scripts.
And also there are folders for the may soon build systems here.
So may and soon are the build systems used by Android, so these build systems are used to build the
entire AOSP project.
So in India, we have the Build a folder here.
So under the Build folder, we can find the source make and there are many other supporting modules
which are needed for the build system and add root.
You can find Ian Reset Abroad asset, so he and we set up data sets, east configuration enrollment,
set up configuration self script, which we run before we start using AOSP.
So if you open it up, you can see all the commands which are available within that.
So if you have already built your system, you are definitely using it.
When you first run in, we set up Dot S-H and then you give the launch command, which actually gives
you the launch menu where you select one boot variant.
And this shell script contains the logic for all the commands which you execute in the terminal.
For example, M M M M stands for making the top of the tree, so you can find all the descriptions here.
We will cover this.
Our Ian Lee set up in detail in a separate video.
Next, we have the CTD or compatibility definition document.
This folder consists of the documentation, so this documentation, you can also find it online.
These are instructions given by Google, which the OEM has to follow to be compatible with the latest
Android release so CBD can be found under a compatibility folder.
So under these, if you go there several record KDDI inside C, D D, there are multiple sections like
we have thirteen sections, so and each of these sections are dedicated to different, different topics.
For example, this one is dedicated to device types and within device types.
You can see different device types supported by Android.
So, for example, handheld device requirements.
This is specific to mobile devices.
The mobile forms and similarly, we have television, so this is specific to television.
This is applicable for all the OEMs who use this Android as the operating system for television.
Similarly, we have watch this is for the wired devices and we have automotive here.
This is for the Android Automotive build.
So with each of the new versions, there will be changes to this documentation.
Similarly, you can find for each topic here like this is software and then the application packaging,
multimedia, hardware, performance and power.
The next to me how courteous seedier stands for Android compatibility test suit.
So here you can find all the modules around the CTS tests on your device.
So insidious tests ensure that your implementation is compatible with this latest AOSP build.
So basically, Android seat is it will run a number of huge number of epics or programs, which will
check different, different implementation of your build.
So in case if one of the implementation fails, it will log that in the report.
So at the end of cities around, you will get a report mentioning whether it was successful or it was
failure.
So you can find the sweetest city tests under the cities folder.
So if you want to learn more about cities test and how to run those, how to start the cities test and
you can look at source code Android dot com.
So there you have detailed information on how to run that.
You can find all the Sidious modules under this particular folder.
Wow.
Wow, wow.